Hit the high seas.
The Sea Beast is a animation, adventure, action film directed by Chris Williams.
When a young girl stows away on the ship of a legendary sea monster hunter, they
launch an epic journey into uncharted waters — and make history to boot.
Jacob Holland (voice), played by Karl Urban.
Maisie Brumble (voice), played by Zaris-Angel Hator.
Captain Crow (voice), played by Jared Harris.
Sarah Sharpe (voice), played by Marianne Jean-Baptiste.
Child 1 (voice), played by Benjamin Plessala.
Child 2 (voice), played by Somali Rose.
The Sea Beast is a 2022 American animated fantasy adventure comedy film directed by Chris
Williams, who co-wrote the screenplay with Nell Benjamin and produced with Jed Schlanger.
The film stars the voices of Karl Urban, Zaris-Angel Hator, Jared Harris, and Marianne Jean-Baptiste
with supporting roles by Kathy Burke, Jim Carter, Doon Mackichan, and Dan Stevens.
It tells the story of a sea-monster hunter and a young orphan girl who joins his
crew on their search for an elusive beast known as the Red Bluster.
The film began a limited theatrical release on June 24,
2022, before debuting on Netflix on July 8.
It received critical acclaim and became one of the most-successful Netflix original animated
films, with 165 million hours viewed over its first five months of release.
The film earned several nominations, including Best Animated Feature at the 95th Academy
Awards, but lost to Guillermo del Toro's Pinocchio, another Netflix animated film.
A sequel is in development, with Williams returning as director.
The film explores themes of ship, orphan, sea
monster, 17th century, lighthearted.
The tone is lighthearted.